

Fernando Peres Valverde

Business Analyst, Data Analyst, Python Developer

Phone, 920 440 669

nandovalverde@gmail.com

Driving license B

My Portfolio

AVAILABLE TO MOVE COUNTRY

Professional Summary

I have 20 years of experience in technology and services, developing solutions for several clients from different economic segments, along with my training that provide me with business knowledge such as Marketing, Administration, Team Management, Project Management, Business Law, Economics, Accounting and Logistics, as well as technical knowledge in Electronics, Python, Pandas, Django, Numpy, Seaborn, Matplotlib, Scikit-learn, Scrapy y Selenium.

Education

UNIVERSITY

Faculdade de Tecnologia de São Paulo FATEC Informática para Negócios (2012 – 2015)

UNIVERSITY

Centro Universitário Fundação Santo André – São Paulo Brasil

Licenciatura e Bacharel em História (2005 – 2009)

TECHNICIAN

Technical course in Electronics – State Technical School of São Paulo (2000 – 2001)

TECHNICIAN

Auto mechanics – SENAI São Paulo – Brazil (1997 – 1998)

Employment History

Self-employed

IT and Infrastructure Consulting (2019 – current)

Business Analyst

Python Developer – Scrapy, Selenium, Numpy, Pandas, Django, PyautoGUI

Founding Partner

Sustine Technologies (2014 – 2019) Santo André – SP Brasil

- IT and infrastructure consulting
- Management of software development projects
- Production management
- Hardware solutions
- Waste Management (Green IT)
- Sale of IT products and systems
- E-Commerce Sales

Computer and Electronics Technician

Jomaris Electronics – Representative Semp Toshiba (2002 – 2014)São Bernardo do Campo – SP Brazil

- Repair of hospital, domestic, industrial and commercial electronic equipment
- Repair of computers and IT equipment
- SMD MicroWelding

Knowledge

- Software Engineering
- Python programming, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, SQL, PL-SQL Oracle
- Django, Numpy, Pandas, Seaborn, Matplotlib, Scikit-learn
- Programming logic
- Team management
- PMBOK, PMI, UML
- Agile Methodologies, Scrum
- 5S Programs, Kanban
- Logistics
- Management
- Business Law
- Economy
- Accounting
- Marketing, Digital Marketing and Social Media

COURSES

- IBM DataScience Professional Certificate
- Security systems
- Waste Management
- Digital certificate
- Agile Methodologies, SCRUM
- Oracle PL-SQL

LANGUAGES

- Advanced Spanish
- Intermediary English

Emplyment History

Electronics Technician

ACM Alarms and Circuits (2001 - 2002) Sao Bernardo do Campo SP Brazil

Truck Mechanic

Avel Apolinário Veículos SA (1997 – 2000) Volkswagen official representative

VOLUNTARY

La Zubia Volunteer Association

- repair of electronic equipment at the Solidarity Store
- -Digital learning for seniors: teaching portable technologies.

SKILLS

- Empathy
- Disciplined
- Methodical
- Responsible
- Ability to make decisions and solve problems
- Ability to work in a team
- Seriousness
- Flexibility
- Creativity
- Self-learning